surveysavvy.com 2011-10-07

# SurveySavvy.com - Your Opinions, Your Marketplace, Your Rewards - Get Paid for Surveys!

## Privacy Policy

**Privacy - Our First Priority**

Luth Research, LLC has been conducting market research through consumer surveys for more than 30 years. Long before the birth of e-business on the Internet, we were at the forefront of protecting the privacy of personal information provided to us by survey respondents. Now, through Luth Research, LLC’s Web site, ****SurveySavvy.com**** , we are able to survey millions of people via the Web -- _giving the consuming public even greater influence over products and services._ Whether we are conducting market research online or offline, the confidentiality of personal information shared with us remains our number one priority. Luth Research, LLC has invested tremendous time and money to ensure that all information we receive from you through the ****SurveySavvy.com**** Web site is secure. The protection of your personal information is our commitment to you. This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices that apply to the online collection of data through the Web site [www.SurveySavvy.com](https://www.surveysavvy.com/ss/ss_index.php).

Luth Research, LLC complies with the principles set forth in the Safe Harbor framework as outlined by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of data from the European Union.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this privacy statement, you should contact [support@surveysavvy.com](mailto:support@surveysavvy.com) by email. Your privacy is important to us. By participating in the Council of Better Business Bureaus’ BBBOnLine® Privacy Program we have made a commitment to meet the program’s strict requirements regarding how we treat your information. We also agree to have our treatment of your information verified by BBBOnLine®. Further information about this program is available at [www.BBBonline.org](http://www.bbbonline.org/)

Luth Research, LLC also conforms to the Council of American Survey Research Organizations (CASRO) Code of Standards and Ethics for Survey Research, the European Society for Opinion and Marketing Research (ESOMAR) ICC/ESOMAR International Code of Marketing and Social Research Practice and the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA).

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

This Privacy Policy only applies to the online information collection practices of ****SurveySavvy.com**** for information collected on this Web site. If you have accessed ****SurveySavvy.com** ** through a link or series of links from other Web site(s), such Web site(s) are not affiliated with ****SurveySavvy.com**** and may have different privacy practices. ****SurveySavvy.com**** is not responsible for the content, practices or policies of such Web site(s).

**Registration**

Registering to participate with Luth Research, LLC at **SurveySavvy.com** is easy. We ask you to fill out a form providing us with certain personal information. We collect information such as name, address, email address, phone number, gender, employment status, household income, education level, marital status, household status, ethnicity and type of computer you use. After you register, we will ask you for additional information through our “Profile Enhancers”, which are used to match you with the most suitable surveys. Completion of “Profile Enhancers” is strictly voluntary.

When you register with **SurveySavvy.com** , you agree: (i) to receive a confirmation email from us confirming your registration; (ii) to receive emails inviting you to participate in surveys with links to the surveys; (iii) when applicable, to receive emails inviting you to participate in voluntary sweepstakes that ****SurveySavvy.com**** may sponsor for its members; and (iv) to receive email responses to questions, comments or updates to your member profile that you submit to the Web site. You also agree to the establishment of your incentive account which shall be credited after you and/or one of your qualified referrals participate in a survey that is completed and validated by **SurveySavvy.com**.

**Use of Information**

The information collected during the registration process allows us to verify your eligibility, to determine which surveys are appropriate for you, and to contact you regarding participation in surveys or in voluntary sweepstakes that **SurveySavvy.com** may sponsor from time to time . We also use individual information to generate demographic data relating to the responses we receive to particular surveys. Survey results are disclosed in the aggregate to the clients of **SurveySavvy.com** who have requested such survey information. Our survey results only report aggregate information about demographic groups. Online surveys may reside on servers located at our offices, a client site or third party site(s) authorized by **SurveySavvy.com**. Survey responses are identified based upon a survey respondent identification number assigned to each respondent. No personally identifiable information is associated with such survey responses or provided to clients or third parties without the respondent's prior “opt-in” consent.

The information you provide through the registration process is completely confidential - we never sell it nor do we share it with third parties without your consent (other than third party service providers who provide services necessary to the operation and use of this Web site and who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of such information that they may have access to as part of their provision of services). Your personal information is also used to credit your incentive account for completed and validated surveys and to compensate you when you request payment of your incentive credit balance. Your personal information (including your social security number) may be required for compliance with tax laws and may be disclosed to the appropriate taxing authorities, as required by law. As we are an independent market research company, ****SurveySavvy.com**** will not use your personal information to sell you products or services.

**Opportunity to Correct/Update Information**

You can correct factual errors, review and/or update your profile at any time from the member's area. To protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. You will receive a follow-up email from ****SurveySavvy.com**** indicating that your member profile has been updated accordingly.

**Consent**

If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated in this Privacy Policy, we will notify you via email. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner.

**Notification of Changes**

If we make any material changes in our privacy practices, we will post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying members of the change. Any material changes in our Privacy Policy will be posted 30 days prior to the date such changes are implemented. In some cases, we will also email members, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices. If you do not agree with the changes made to this Privacy Policy, you may unsubscribe.

**Security of Personal Information**

The extraordinary data encryption team at Luth Research, LLC has developed one of the only market research sites in the world that utilizes Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption of personal information. SSL "scrambles" all your personal information -- name, address, telephone number, email address and password -- when you click on "Next" to transmit your registration form to us. Your information is not reassembled until it safely reaches our server. Furthermore, you may go to our member's area at any time to check on your personal information or to view your incentive credit balance -- but you will be required to enter your previously registered email address and password before accessing any individualized data. Any information you send to us -- corrections to your personal information, requests for payment, etc. -- will be encrypted by SSL. ****SurveySavvy.com**** has expended significant resources in acquiring server, database and firewall technology designed to maintain the security and confidentiality of your personal information. The security of our Web site also depends, in part, upon you. You will be responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password and are fully responsible for all activities that occur under your email address and password. You agree to immediately notify ****SurveySavvy.com**** of any unauthorized use of your email address and password.

**Use of Cookies and Web Server Logs**

All **SurveySavvy.com** members are required to use private email addresses and confidential passwords when logging on to complete online surveys. The engineers of our data encryption team are constantly monitoring **SurveySavvy.com** 's database to ensure the integrity of online consumer survey responses.

Whenever you visit **SurveySavvy.com** or complete one of our online surveys, a small data file called a cookie is attached to your hard drive. The cookie contains information that allows us to recognize registered members. A cookie cannot read data off your hard drive or read cookie files created by other sites. You can prevent cookies from being attached to your hard drive by turning them off in your Internet browser. You can still visit **SurveySavvy.com** and participate in surveys even if your computer does not accept cookies. 

Like most Web sites, we collect standard Web server logs for analysis. The logging method we use includes IP address, dates/times, browser type, page hit, and referral pages. In addition, a cookie is issued that allows us to determine whether a visitor has visited us in the past. All information collected is used for either broad demographic analysis or system administration. None of the log file information collected is linked to personal information.

**Unsubscribe**

You don't have to participate in every survey; if you don't respond, we will contact you later about another survey. If at any time you decide that you don't want to participate in our surveys anymore, you can unsubscribe and we will send you an email indicating that we have processed your request to unsubscribe. After we have received and processed your request to unsubscribe, you will no longer receive emails from **SurveySavvy.com** inviting you to participate in surveys.

**Sweepstakes**

From time to time, **SurveySavvy.com** may hold a sweepstakes available to its current members, new members or specific sections of its membership. Participation in these sweepstakes is voluntary. Sweepstakes prize winners will be notified of their prizes by email. Prize winnings will be deposited in member’s incentive accounts. As a condition to entering into such sweepstakes, members agree that **SurveySavvy.com** may use their name, hometown and home state for marketing purposes and may display their name, home town and home state on this Web site under a list of winners for each sweepstakes. A link or other reference to the location of the sweepstakes rules will be provided in the invitation to participate in the sweepstakes.

**Children's Privacy**

**SurveySavvy.com** firmly believes in maintaining the security and confidentiality of all visitors to this Web site, regardless of age. **SurveySavvy.com** complies with all applicable provisions of the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). Where a parent who is a member of **SurveySavvy.com** has indicated in their member profile that members of their household include children, **SurveySavvy.com** may, from time to time, request that such parent allow one or more of those children to respond to surveys specifically designed for children. The children of such members may only respond to such surveys on this Web site by using the email address and password of one of their parents with the prior consent of such parent. Surveys specifically designed for children to respond to shall relate to products and services that are age appropriate and shall only collect the following general demographic information about the respondent: the child’s age, gender and zip code (or larger geographic area) where the child resides. Such surveys shall not collect more personal information about the child than is reasonably necessary for marketing research purposes. The child’s survey responses shall be used for the same purposes and shall be subject to the same obligations, restrictions and conditions as any other member survey response.

By providing an email address and password for the use of this Web site to any child, the parent has consented to the child’s participation in and response to surveys through this Web site. Parents have the right to: (i) consent to the collection and use of personal information of their children without also consenting to the disclosure of such information to third parties; (ii) review personal information collected from their children; (iii) request that personal information of their children be deleted; and (iv) refuse the further collection of personal information of their children. In the event a parent believes that their child is using their email address and password to access this Web site without authorization, has registered as a member of this Web site using false information, or wishes to exercise any of the parental rights set forth in this section, such parent may contact us at Luth Research, LLC. 1365 Fourth Avenue, San Diego, California 92101 **(888) 588-4258** or email us by using our handy [ Contact Us ](mailto:support@surveysavvy.com) form.

**Unsolicited Emails**

Luth Research, LLC and **SurveySavvy.com** never spam or send unsolicited commercial emails. Members who spam in order to generate referrals are ineligible for any compensation from **SurveySavvy.com** and will be permanently disqualified from participation in **SurveySavvy.com**. See our Frequently Asked Questions page for a definition of spam.

**General**

By visiting this Web site, you agree that this Privacy Policy and the Terms and Conditions govern your use of the Web site. All disputes over privacy shall be governed as set forth in this Privacy Policy or in the Terms and Conditions, including applicable law, arbitration rules and limitations on damages. You should review the Web site periodically for any changes to this Privacy Policy and the Terms and Conditions.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions, concerns, or comments about our privacy policies or practices, we would like to know what they are so we can address them. Please contact us at **(888) 588-4258** or email us by using our handy [ Contact Us](mailto:support@surveysavvy.com) form.

Effective Date: December 15, 2005
